Contact

kmayorgarn@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kmayorgarn (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

CCRN

CFRN

CEN

Languages

Spanish

Certifications

Certified Emergency Nurse (CEN®)
Certified Flight Registered Nurse
(CFRN®)
CCRN

Karla Mayorga, MLS, BSN, RN

JD Expected 2023 at Willamette University College of Law Portland, Oregon

Summary

I am a bilingual registered nurse specializing in the treatment of critical care patients across the lifespan. Areas of nursing experience and training I specialize in include the following: emergency and trauma services, neurosurgical intensive care, intensive care, prehospital/inter-facility rotary and fixed-wing flight, and interventional radiology.

I have advanced specialty training and extensive experience in airway management techniques, rapid sequence intubation, sedation, ventilator initiation and management, cricothyrotomy procedure, escharotomy procedure, needle decompression, chest tube insertion and management, advanced hemodynamic monitoring, intraaortic balloon pump management, external ventricular and lumbar drain management, central line placement and management, high risk obstetrics, neonatal delivery and care, pediatrics, geriatrics, field triage, response to mass casualty incidents, trauma care, rural medicine, and flight physiology.

Active Nursing Certifications: Certified Emergency Nurse, CCRN (Adult Critical/Acute Care), Certified Flight Registered Nurse

Active nursing licenses in Oregon, California, and Arizona.

Experience

Oregon Health and Science University
Registered Nurse - Interventional Radiology - per diem
March 2019 - Present (1 year 4 months)

Banner - University Medical Center 12 years 3 months

RN Manager - Emergency Department & Trauma April 2018 - January 2019 (10 months)

Phoenix, Arizona Area

Registered Nurse Emergency Department June 2015 - March 2018 (2 years 10 months)

Phoenix, Arizona Area

Banner Staffing Services Registered Nurse - ED & ICU October 2012 - June 2015 (2 years 9 months)

Phoenix, Arizona Area

Neurosurgical Intensive Care Unit Registered Nurse November 2011 - October 2012 (1 year)

Phoenix, AZ

Formerly, Banner Good Samaritan Medical Center, Level I Trauma

Emergency Department Registered Nurse July 2009 - November 2011 (2 years 5 months) Gilbert, AZ

Banner Gateway Medical Center

Spanish Medical Interpreter November 2006 - June 2009 (2 years 8 months) Gilbert and Mesa, AZ

Banner Mesa & Banner Gateway Medical Centers

Act as a bridge of communication by providing accurate and complete interpretation.

Air Methods
Flight Registered Nurse II
October 2015 - August 2017 (1 year 11 months)
Yuma, Arizona Area

California Shock Trauma Air Rescue (CALSTAR) Flight Registered Nurse II January 2014 - February 2015 (1 year 2 months) Bay Area, CA

Dignity Health
Emergency Department Registered Nurse - PRN
June 2012 - August 2013 (1 year 3 months)
Gilbert, AZ

Mercy Gilbert Medical Center

Education

Willamette University College of Law JD expected · (2019 - 2023)

Sandra Day O'Connor College of Law at Arizona State University Master's degree, Legal Studies · (2017 - 2018)

Grand Canyon University

Bachelor of Science in Nursing (BSN), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2013 - 2014)

Gateway Community College
Associate of Science (A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2007 - 2009)